Xavier University Williams College of Business records
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Xavier University Williams College of Business records
1952-2017
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Xavier University (Cincinnati, Ohio). Williams College of Business
2 linear feet (4 boxes)
This is a small collection of records originating with the business programs at Xavier University. The Williams College of Business is the most recent name for the business school at Xavier. Documents include historical information on the development of the college, correspondence and meeting minutes, conference and institute materials, accreditation documents, publications and various other materials.
XUA-83
Scope and Content
This is a small collection of records that reflect some of the activities of the business program at Xavier University. Documents include historical information on the development of the college, correspondence and meeting minutes, conference and institute materials, accreditation documents, publications and various other materials.
Not specified
Statement of Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: Series I: Historical Information, Correspondence and Minutes, 1959-2008 Series II: Materials from Conferences and Institutes, 1954-1993 Series III: AACSB Accreditation, 1984-2000 Series IV: Publications and Miscellaneous Materials, 1952-2010
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Accruals
XUA2017-001
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Business education
Detailed Description of The Collection
- Historical Information, Correspondence and Minutes, 1959-2017
  - History of College; Deans of College, 1961-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Establishing a Business College, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1952-1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1975-1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes of Administrative Team Meetings, 1978-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Minutes of Faculty Meetings (1978-1991); Minutes of Committee Meetings (1987-1991) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CBA Business Advisory Board, 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Distinguished Speaker Series, 2017 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Conference and Institute Materials, 1954-1993
  - Annual Greater Cincinnati Business Conferences, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Conferences on Business Problems of Catholic Institutions Brochures, 1954-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Conference on Business Problems of Catholic Institutions, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Conference on Business Problems of Catholic Institutions, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conference on Business Problems of Catholic Institutions, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Business Problems of Catholic Institutions, 1961-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Business Problems of Catholic Institutions, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Institute of Business Services, Projects and Services, 1958-1959 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Institute of Business Services Placement Brochure, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Institute for Business and Community Services Brochures, 1977; 1993 April 16 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- AACSB Accreditation, 1984-2000
  - AACSB Accreditation Self Study 1984, Part 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - AACSB Accreditation Self Study 1984, Part 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - AACSB Accreditation Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - AACSB Accreditation Self Study 1993, Volume 1, 1993 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AACSB Accreditation Self Study 1993, Volume 2, 1993 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - AACSB Accreditation Self Study 1993: Strategic Direction Package, 1993 June 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - AACSB Accreditation Supplementary Attachments, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - AACSB Accreditation Activities in Response to Assessment Outcomes, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Publications and Various Other Materials, 1952-2010
  - MBA Survey of Alumni, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Syllabus of Course BA 202: Research in Business, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - College Inaugural Event 1992; Annual Awards Dance, 1979-1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Off Campus MBA Programs, 1974-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Associate Degree Program for IBM, 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Publication: MBA Briefs, 1978-1981 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    These are some issues of the College of Business Administration publication. This title was supposed to be published twice per year. Several issues are missing.
  - Publication: CBA Today, 1985-1989 (Box 4, Folder 6-A)
  - Publication: CBA Today, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Publication: CBA Today, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Brochures, Pamphlets, Newspaper Clippings, 1952-2010 (Box 4, Folder 9)